<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Jerm Disorder]]></title>
  <link href="http://jermul.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jermul.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-14T11:53:20-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://jermul.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Jerm]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Philosoraptor Says]]></title>
    <link href="http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/05/14/philosoraptor-says/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-14T11:01:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/05/14/philosoraptor-says</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m sorry, I lied to you all in my last blog entry&#8230;<!-- more--></p>

<p>I told you that I was super persistent and super driven. Well, that&#8217;s not entirely true. The truth is, I am those things but only because I find programming so damn fun.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve never been terribly diligent. I haven&#8217;t made a New Years Resolution in over a decade because I know I most likely won&#8217;t keep it. I never stick to diets for very long. And, I still can&#8217;t dunk a basketball, even though I promised myself I one day would (still holding out hope on this one).</p>

<p>And then along comes programming into my life. Lazy you say? <a href="http://pragprog.com/book/ltp2/learn-to-program">Chris Pine says to be proactively lazy!</a> What&#8217;s that? You&#8217;re a glutton? Gorge yourself on a cornucopia of knowledge that would make Thanksgivings itself blush:</p>

<p><img src="http://i820.photobucket.com/albums/zz123/dragoon976/Blog/cornucopia.png">
<small>Source: Ready set Rails</small></p>

<p>Here&#8217;s the thing with me. If I really like something, it&#8217;s much easier to motivate myself to get through the tedious stuff to get to the awesome stuff. I&#8217;ll let my buddy Philosoraptor sum it up:</p>

<p><img src="http://qkme.me/3uebau"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tealeaf Academy May Cohort]]></title>
    <link href="http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/05/10/tealeaf-academy-may-cohort/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-10T00:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/05/10/tealeaf-academy-may-cohort</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently joined a code boot-camp of sorts called Tealeaf Academy. My cohort began on May 4th and will run me about twelve weeks.</p>

<p>Per the last live session of the course, some classmates asked me what resources I used to self-learn programming, so I will be posting them here&#8230;<!-- more --> Best of all, they&#8217;re all free! It&#8217;s amazing how many resources we have at our fingertips.</p>

<p>I think a little background on me would be relevant because people should know that I am just an average guy. I&#8217;ve been familiar with computers since a young age (i&#8217;m now in my low 30s) but did <strong> not </strong> have any programming experience prior to mid January 13&#8217;. I took one C++ course in junior college that I dropped out of cause it was too hard. Since January, I have been self-teaching full time due to wanting a career change (I used to be an administrator in healthcare, where I was the &#8220;IT&#8221; guy).</p>

<p>I really am not being modest when I say I’m not particularly smart nor gifted. The good thing is that it doesn&#8217;t take being a &#8216;genius&#8217; or to be &#8216;technically gifted&#8217; to &#8216;get&#8217; programming. I can liken it most to learning to play an instrument. At first, you suck and it&#8217;s super intimidating how far you have to go to even feel decent. I often feel dejected when thinking about how far I still need to go to get where I want to be. However, unlike musicians, developers are in such high demand that you don&#8217;t have to be exceptional to get an amazing career. In fact, there&#8217;s even a trend of companies paying employees to learn to code on their dime!</p>

<p>And all you need to get good enough for that level is to show you&#8217;re persistent enough and have the drive to get through those initial hurdles. Prove that you&#8217;re willing to be labeled a nerd, that you want to learn the difference between all those three and four letter acronyms like MVC DRY NODE JAVA RoR and ACDC, and that you can get beyond “hello world” even if it took you four hours to realize all you were missing was a semi-colon. The fact that you&#8217;re here, in this tiny corner of the world wide web is a good start.</p>

<p>I will flatter myself by saying that I am super persistent and I am super driven. The beauty of it is that everybody else can be too, with enough demand to go around for everyone:</p>

<p><img src="http://i820.photobucket.com/albums/zz123/dragoon976/Blog/code_graphics.png">
<small>Computer Science Graduates vs. Jobs. Source: code.org</small>
<img src="http://i820.photobucket.com/albums/zz123/dragoon976/Blog/code_graphics2.png">
<small>Computer Science Job Outlook. Source: code.org</small></p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to separate the list into three sections: General Programming, Ruby, and RoR (Ruby on Rails) and listed from top to bottom in each section for what I felt personally helped most. If you have zero programming experience, I highly suggest doing them in order. You can do the Ruby and GP sections simultaneously but leave RoR till you at least tried the other two for a couple weeks. Here are the lists:</p>

<h3><u>General Programming</u></h3>


<p>
  Stanford CS106A Programming Methodology – Truly engaging course. Often considered a weeder class, but if you can get through this course then I&#8217;m pretty sure you can get through anything else on this list.
</p>


<p>
  MIT Intro to Computer Science – good overview of the how and why we do programming.
</p>


<p>
  Natashatherobot - A lot of the links here come from this blog. A real person sharing her trials and tribulations learning to code. Very humble, yet very inspiring and ambitious. Makes you feel good about your choice to learn to code.
</p>


<p> 
  Udacity.com – Video courses online. Interactive online college classes. Everything from general CS, to web development, to physics courses.
</p>


<h3><u>Ruby</u></h3>


<p>
  Codecademy.com – Amazing resources for general understanding of multiple languages. I found the javascript courses were constructed better than the Ruby courses, but ymmv. 
</p>


<p>
  Rubymonk – teaching then quizzing, with increasing difficulty. One of my favorites. Practice the flow of programming.
</p>


<p>
  RPCFN, Ruby Koans, Codequizzes – ruby quizzes to challenge yourself.
</p>


<p>
  Rubythehardway – ruby exercises that emphasizes repetition and practice. Some say that since it was rewritten from a different language, it misses some of Ruby&#8217;s special nuances. I still found it helpful.
</p>


<h3><u>RoR</u></h3>


<p>
  Michael Hartl&#8217;s tutorial – although a lot will recommend this one right away, I only suggest you tackle it with your own project in mind and with a solid foundation in Ruby first. Challenge yourself when doing it, as otherwise its very easy to fall into just copying code and not understanding it. I personally started with this, but if I could do it again I wouldn&#8217;t, although I still refer to it all the time.
</p>


<p>
  Railscasts – Video tutorials mostly involving the implementation of gems. Invaluable for all sorts of RoR practices as well. 
</p>


<p>
  Rails for Zombies – They recently did a pretty big makeover and I keep intending to go back, but haven&#8217;t had the time. 
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confessional]]></title>
    <link href="http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/03/25/Confessional/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-25T18:24:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://jermul.github.com/blog/2013/03/25/Confessional</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
  It&#8217;s been a few months now, and I feel I have a confession to make: I have had a mistress, and her name is Ruby&#8230;<!-- more --> I spend day and night with her. I eat with her, I play with her, I work with her. Even when I&#8217;m not with Ruby, I am constantly thinking about her, even dreaming about her. 
</p>


<p>
  The best thing is that my wife totally supports it.  
</p>


<p>
    I thought about extending the analogy to Rails as well, but we won&#8217;t go there. I have decided dedicate myself to becoming a Ruby on Rails web developer. The purpose of my blog is to detail my path to enlightenment of getting to know Ruby and Rails, and to profess my love by documenting it.
</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
